Guide to the Laura Foreman Papers 1949-2001 MSS 122
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VII: Film
  Series VII contains a small amount of moving image documentations captured on film instead of video.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - New G & S Super 8, undated (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0459)
      Gauge: Super8mm
    - How to Organize a Film Workshop, 1978 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0460)
      Gauge: 16mm
- Series VIII: Audio
  Series VIII contains audio recordings, and is currently awaiting processing. For more information on this series, contact a Fales Archivist.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
  - Subseries B: Originals
- Series IX: Objects, 1.25 linear feet 1 Paige Carton
  Series IX contains various items once owned by Foreman or employed in her artworks, including props from dance performances.
  The objects in Series IX are arranged thematically, if rather loosely. Every object has its own identification number. The first objects listed are those that pertain to Foreman's dance career. Those that were difficult to align with any part of Foreman's career follow.
  - Photographic Print - unidentified event, mounted on foam core and 11x14 card, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0001)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0002)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0003)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0004)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0005)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0006)
  - Silver whistle with chain, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0007)
  - Black whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0008)
  - Black whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0009)
  - Small speaker / microphone, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0010)
  - Small speaker / microphone, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0011)
  - Choreographers Theatre button; reads "Modern Dance Power", undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0012)
  - Costume worn by Satoru Shimazaki in Entries, 1978 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0013)
  - Large copper bell on a long, multi-colored beaded necklace, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0014)
  - Six copper bells and multi-colored beads tied on a leather string, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0015)
  - Five small copper bells tied on an orange rope; label attached reads "Camel Bells", undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0016)
  - Five small gold bells tied on an orange rope, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0017)
  - Two small gold bells tied on an orange rope, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0018)
  - Copper cowbell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0019)
  - Gold bell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0020)
  - Small silver bell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0021)
  - Button-shaped silver bell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0022)
  - Thin orange, green and white rope tied in a bow, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0023)
  - Small tambourine, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0024)
  - Ziploc bag containing four keys; marked "Play Keys", undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0025)
  - Plastic zipper case containing CCT Corporate Seal Embosser, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0026)
  - Composers and Choreographers Theatre Corporate Seal Embosser, 1966 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0027)
  - Medal in case, from International Film and TV Festival of New York, 1981 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0028)
  - "Dancing Finger Bear" toy, in original packaging, 1981 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0029)
  - "Bag Full of Laughs" Toy, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0030)
    D batteries removed in the for preservation purposes
  - "Bag Full of Laughs" toy, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0031)
  - "Baby Piano" toy, in original packaging, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0032)
  - Six intertwined red and white pipe cleaners, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0033)
  - Small jewel box, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0034)
  - Small knitted kite made of yarn and two popsicle sticks, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0035)
- Oversize Series I: Files
  - Apartment Floor Plans, undated (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Apartment Floor Plans, undated (Map-case 3.R, Folder 1)
  - Birthday Card for Laura Foreman, 1974 (Map-case 3.R, Folder 2)
  - Choreoconcerts Flyer Draft, 1974 (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Choreographers' Theatre Flyer Drafts, undated (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - Composers' and Choreographers' Theatre Disbursement Ledgers, 1973-1975 (Box 153, Folder 3-4)
  - High School Class photographs with student signatures, 1952, 1955 (Map-case 3.R, Folder 3)
  - Photocopied Drawings, undated (Box 153, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy - Brooklyn Journal, 1978 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    includes poems and writing by Foreman's friend, Palmer Hasty
  - Press, 1990 (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Schematic Drawings, undated (Box 153, Folder 7)
  - Schematic Drawings, undated (Box 155, Folder 2)
  - Souyun Yi Gallery Design Charts, c1998 (Box 153, Folder 8)
- Oversize Series IV: Photographic Material
  - "Coney Island Cray-Pas", 1981 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    Contact Sheets
  - "Coney Island Cray-Pas", 1981 (Box 153, Folder 9)
  - "Wallwork" in Paris and Stockholm (by John Watts), 1981 (Box 152, Folder 3-4)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 152, Folder 5)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 153, Folder 10)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 155, Folder 3-5)
  - Personal, undated (Box 152, Folder 6)
  - Portraits and performance photos of John Watts, 1977 (Box 153, Folder 11)
  - Photos of unidentified persons and events, undated (Box 152, Folder 7)
  - Photos of unidentified persons and events, undated (Box 153, Folder 12)
- Oversize Series V: Artworks, Sketches and Posters
  - "Birdhouse as Metaphor" Sketches, 1986, undated (Box 153, Folder 13-17)
  - Chambers Street Artists Exhibition Poster, 1981 (Box 155, Folder 7)
  - Costume Design Sketches, undated (Box 153, Folder 18-19)
  - Fiber R/evolution Exhibition Poster, Milwaukee Art Museum, 1986 (Map-case 3.R, Folder 4)
  - "Gum Art" Sketch, undated (Box 152, Folder 8)
  - "Heirlooms" Posters, 1977 (Box 155, Folder 8)
  - "Luncheonette Art Work" Sketch, 1984 (Box 155, Folder 9)
  - Mixed Media Paintings, undated (Box 153, Folder 20-22)
  - "Not For Sale" Exhibition Poster, undated (Box 152, Folder 9)
  - Paintings from "Vermont Colony School", 1988 (Box 153, Folder 23-28)
  - Shacks of America Photocollages, undated (Box 152, Folder 10)
  - Shacks of America Photocollages, undated (Map-case 3.R, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 152, Folder 11-12)
  - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 155, Folder 10-11)
  - Spare Parts Exhibition Poster, 1983 (Box 155, Folder 12)
  - "Wallwork" Poster, 1981 (Box 155, Folder 13)
  - "Word Painting" / "I have nothing to paint and I'm painting it", 1983 (Box 152, Folder 13)
  - Untitled Artworks, undated (Box 154, Folder 1-2)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Box 152, Folder 14-16)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Box 155, Folder 14-18)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Box 154, Folder 3-37)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Map-case 3.R, Folder 6-7)